A Guide to the Frank Harris Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7453-g
Frank Harris Collection 1924-1925
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7435-g
8 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1985 Nov
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Frank Harris to Percival Hinton, 1924 Mar 15; ALS, 2 p.
    [Agrees with
    Times
    reviewer's assessment on the best stories in his latest book; discusses his four volumes of
    Contemporary Portraits
    . ]
  - Frank Harris to Percival Hinton, 1924 May 8; ALS, 2 p.
    [Intrigued by his suggestions of future subjects of another volume of
    warns him that one must have intimate knowledge of a person to do a good portrait; says Bernard Shaw has invited him to London to meet the young literary figures; dislikes England's legal system because of the Oscar Wilde trial and prefers the French judicial system.]
  - Frank Harris to Percival Hinton, 1924 Jun 1; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for his letter and excellent article; only English musician he knows is Josef Holbrooke; sends a copy of
    My Life and Loves
  - Frank Harris to Percival Hinton, 1924 Jun 18; ALS, 2 p.
    [Informs him that he will send a copy of
    by express rail package; says the authorities confiscated the one he had sent by mail as obscene material; speaks about the harassment of booksellers; informs him that he has nearly finished second volume; is much more interesting than the first because it "contains the intimate sex-history of a dozen of my most famous contemporaries"; Bernard Shaw has described
    Life and Confessions of Oscar Wilde
    as the best biography extant.]
  - Frank Harris to Percival Hinton, 1925 Mar 30; ALS, 1 p.
    [Asks if he has received his fourth volume of
    describes
    Unpath'd Waters
    as his best volume of short stories; describes the second volume of
    as the "frankest book ever written"; will be published in May.]
  - Frank Harris to Percival Hinton, 1925 Jul 10; ALS, 1 p.
    [Claims that Joyce's
    Ulysses
    is more significant than
    as a symbol of revolt despite its later publication; claims membership in "the Second Renaissance...the New Paganism...or in the new Naturalism which couples Darwin with Jesus"; discusses his third volume in progress; describes poor financial status.]
- Printed
  - My Life and Loves from Birth to Manhood by Frank Harris, Prospectus, 4 p.
  - My Life: Vol. 2 From 1875-1890 by Frank Harris, n.d.; Prospectus, 4 p.